NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files. 6174/011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- RTA Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  Rhinecliff Teachers Association minutes, April 19, 1993, and April 11, 1994; memo to superintendent re alleged unilateral change in sick bank, May 10, 1993; memo to staff (from Pius senior vice president for residential services) re morale issues, October 1, 1993; memo to superintendent re theft of money from teacher's purse, repeated request for lockers for faculty, May 16, 1994; memo from superintendent that lockers would be provided, May 11, 1994; letter to superintendent from Joseph Salvia, president of teachers association, demanding district investigation of allegation of racism against Salvia, noting involvement of Human Rights Commission, accusing accuser of paranoia, April 6, 1994; letter from Salvia to teachers association re district plans to excess (lay off) teachers because of a reduction in resident intake, December 3, 1993; letter from Salvia to superintendent expressing concern over teacher-student ratio in disciplinary unit, September 21, 1993; related memo, September 17, 1993; letter from Salvia to superintendent re plans for a day treatment program as a mandatory subject of bargaining, December 16, 1993; letter demanding negotiation re creation of a separate middle school, August 25, 1993; memo from Salvia to teachers association membership, criticizing remarks by principal that school could close, faculty could not work together, October 18, 1993
- RTA Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  Calendar for 1994-95; letter to staff from principal re need to attract more students, keep a professional attitude, June 23, 1995; letter from Pius XII senior vice president for residential services re Rhinecliff area-resident concerns re reckless driving by staff, lack of courtesy, and lack of adequate supervision of students, June 24, 1994; memos re changes in prescription coverage, seniority/longevity/tenure; letter to principal from teacher, objecting to lack of support in dealing with disruptive student, November 17, 1994; ongoing memos between principal and teachers association president re review of lesson plans, insubordination, related grievances
- RTA Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  Grievances for failure by district to provide budget information, including salary figures; NYSUT memo to local presidents, and financial controls checklist, September 22, 1995; NYSUT information bulletin and memo to K-12 local presidents re shared decisionmaking (Commissioner's Regulations 100.11) biannual review, November 27, 1995; memo to after-school staff re need to fill out paperwork documenting extra-curricular activities, in case of audit by federal granting agencies, October 3, 1995; agenda for meeting of NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office, November 30, 1995; AWOL Procedure for Residents Missing from Campus, effective 11/9/95; letters to NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin appealing for increased effort in lobbying legislature and State Education Department for more funds for Special Act Schools, especially for salaries; memos to district re compensation and scheduling issues
- RTA Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  Minutes of NDU (restricted unit) Planning Committee, 2/7/96, with cover memo to teachers association president Joseph Salvia re concerns; letters between Salvia and principal Leslie Hurd, superintendent Ronald Rosen and others re negotiations, grievances, and requests for information; requests for release time from several teachers to attend Board of Education meeting; job description for Committee on Special Education chairperson; memo re lack of notice to staff for Halloween speakers program, October 30, 1996; report re parking lot vandalism; memo to Salvia from superintendent re status of preparations for intensive treatment unit, possible need for assignment of teachers if no volunteers came forward, June 28, 1996
- RTA Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  Correspondence re maintenance issues for gym (cleaning schedule, contamination of drinking water, leaking water on to floor); letter of resignation from director of physical education; letters of reprimand from principal to director of physical education; Freedom of Information requests re salary figures and Board minutes; request for list of members of Sick Bank Committee; position statement by Rhinecliff Teachers Association re salary adjustments, June 2, 1986; letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to RTA president informing him of his appointment to serve on NYSUT Task Force on AIDS, December 13, 1985; letter from Salvia to executive director of Pius XII Youth and Family Services, objecting to Rhinecliff superintendent's refusal to grant a professional leave day to attend NYSUT Task Force on AIDS meeting, April 9, 1986
- Staff Meetings, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  Agendas and minutes
- RTA Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  Memo from president of Board of Education, announcing consolidation of superintendent position between Rhinecliff and Sugar Loaf school districts, April 13, 1999; memo to all teachers from president of Board of Education re 3020-a (insubordination) hearing against RTA president, March 11, 1999, with attached statement by RTA asserting charges were retaliation for union activities; requests to negotiate; requests for information, noting violation of contract; request that charitable solicitations not be made at staff meetings, March 15, 1999; letters re indoor air quality, security of technology lab, problems with access to buildings; letter giving notice of departure of superintendent at end of contract, March 1, 1999; letter from RTA requesting involvement in search for new superintendent, March 16, 1999; letters from RTA objecting to exclusion from Board of Education meeting, omission of items from minutes
- NYSUT Conference, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  Correspondence re paid release time for attendance at NYSUT Local Presidents' Conference, April 20, 1998; conference program; NYSUT Constitution; flyers re NYSUT Representative Assembly
- Grievances, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  Grievance and arbitration materials between Rhinecliff Teachers' Association and Rhinecliff Union Free School District re compensation for training seminar held beyond regular work day
- Agency Contracts, 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 64)
  Pius XII Youth and Family Services 1993-94 and 1991-92 operational services agreement, health services agreement, and space allocation agreement for Rhinecliff school district; State of the Agency report from the office of the president, September 1992
- Employee Assistance Program, 1985-1987 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  E.A.P. Policy Statement submitted to Rhinecliff Union Free School District by Rhinecliff Teachers Association, April 21, 1987; letter from RTA president informing district of unanimous decision of teachers association not to participate in district-administered E.A.P.; letter to RTA president from NYSUT field representative, confirming that locals should not participate in management- administered E.A.P.s; Remarks of Thomas F. Hartnett, director, Governor's Office of Employee Relations, Employee Assistance Program Coordinator Conference, October 11, 1985; articles re employee assistance programs
- RTA Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Freedom of Information requests from RTA to district for salary, budget, and other information; list of unanswered correspondence, April 2, 1990; organizational chart and list of board of directors of Pius XII School, Inc.; materials re smoking policy, 1988-89; RTA position statement re salary adjustment, June 2, 1986; Program Cabinet minutes, May 29, 1987; list of RTA executive committee members for 1990-91; memo to RTA members re unresponsiveness of district administration re reappointment of nontenured staff, June 1, 1990; letter from RTA president to principal, objecting to unannounced classroom visit as disruptive, March 26, 1990; letter to district from Salvia questioning rental agreements with Pius XII agency, February 26, 1990
- Joe Salvia-Smoking Policy, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  Letter from RTA president re smoking policy as a mandatory bargaining topic; letter from Salvia objecting to use of taxpayer money to lobby against legislation proposed by state Board of Regents, November 16, 1989
- RTA, 1986-1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  Agreement between Rhinecliff Union Free School District and Rhinecliff Teachers' Association, July 1, 1986 through June 30, 1988; stipulation of agreement; vote tally, April 30, 1990; agenda for association meeting, June 4, 1990; teacher salary schedule, 1989-90; letter from NYSUT Regional Director Jan Conti re transfer of field representative/labor relations specialist Linda Stanczik, assignment of temporary replacement Wally Fults to serve local teachers union, June 25, 1990
- Special Ed. Regulations, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Text of Commissioner's Regulations Part 200 -- Children with Handicapping Conditions
- Pius XII Youth and Family Services, 1985-1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  Lease agreements between Pius XII agency and Rhinecliff Union Free School District
- Pius XII Youth and Family Services, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  Operational services agreements between Pius XII Holy Cross Campus and Rhinecliff school district
- Fixed Asset Change Form, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  Freedom of Information request to Rhinecliff district superintendent from Rhinecliff Teachers Association re equipment on loan; Fixed Asset Changes Forms re move of pool table to recreation room, move of vault
- School Budgets, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  Freedom of Information request to Rhinecliff superintendent re school budget; Rhinecliff Union Free School District annual school budget, 1989-90, filed with State Education Department
- Student Handbook (Box 18, Folder 9)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Student Handbook; Stipulation of Agreement between the negotiating committees of district and teachers association, July 21, 1986
- NYSUT, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  Constitution of Rhinecliff Union Free School Teachers Association, March 1976; appendix, The Code of Ethics of the Education Profession
- RTA-Schematic COC (Box 18, Folder 11)
  Organizational charts
- Negotiations SPR, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  Newspaper clipping re Redhook teachers 8.5% salary increase, with teacher salary schedule, April 1
- NYSUT Registration, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  NYSUT dues statements to Rhinecliff Teachers Association
- TB Program, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  Memo to superintendent from RTA president re verification of TB (tuberculosis) testing, with copy of test results from doctor, April 14, 1997; Freedom of Information request from Salvia to superintendent asking for the number of students who had tested positive for tuberculosis since September 1996, and the number still in the population; reply form superintendent, stating that no such records were kept by the district; flyers re TB, with cover letter to Salvia from Dutchess County Department of Health, February 3, 1997
- Aggressions, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  Memo to all staff re aggression against staff and faculty members, March 27, 1991; aggression report, May 21, 1991; related correspondence
- Faculty Meetings, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  Agendas for faculty meetings, September 17 and 24, October 1, 15 and 23, November 5, 1990; list of parents attending Parents' Day, November 3, 1990
- Supporting Data, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  List of 1988 space allocation; RTA motion re lobbying issues
- Schedule Calculators, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  Rhinecliff school calendar; teachers' schedule
- Sick Time, 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  Forms for calculation of sick time
- Private School and Compliance, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  Letter and attached materials from State Education Department re salary improvement program to address the turnover problem in Special Act schools, June 18, 1986; State Education Department program review for Rhinecliff district, June 24, 1986; compliance plan materials from Rhinecliff
- Administrative Directives Policy, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  Memo from principal to all staff that classroom door windows should remain unobstructed; memo re smoke-free campus; job description for district principal, principal, guidance counselor, and other senior staff; organization chart
- Board of Education, 1997-1999 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  Amended agenda for October 21, 1997, meeting; minutes of September 16, 1997, meeting; memo from RTA president to president of Board of Education, asking that RTA be kept involved in search for new superintendent, March 16, 1999; letter from Salvia requesting that the RTA be involved in selection process for members of the Board of Education, February 24, 1997; petition by members of RTA in support of Salvia, alleging that disciplinary action against him was scapegoating, April 29, 1997; organizational chart; letter from Savia objecting to the scheduling of work days on Jewish holy days, March 17, 1998; contact numbers for members of Board of Education; correspondence re change in Board meeting date, posting of public notice, 1996-97
- Budget Material RTA, 1987-1991 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  1989-1990 and 1990-91 Rhinecliff Teachers Association Proposed Annual Budgets
- Budget Material RUFSD, 1996-2000 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Annual Budget 1999-2000; budget modification summary, November 22, 1996
- Calendars, 1978-1988 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  Draft, proposed, and approved Rhinecliff school calendars
- Cluster Program, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  Letter to superintendent from popular, long-term Rhinecliff teacher, declining assignment to new Intensive Learning Program, objecting that assignment was not discussed with him ahead of time, July 22, 1996; correspondence re cluster system; notes from cluster meetings
- Coalition-Special Act, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  Summary of NYSUT meeting re Special Act Schools, November 6, 1991; letter from Special Act Union Leadership Council (NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO) to union presidents, re meeting with superintendent's coalition, possibility of forming joint lobbying effort, May 10, 1990; text of legislation in NYS Assembly authorizing Education Commissioner to study possible inequities in funding methodologies for Special Act schools
- Copy Machine, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  Memos from principal re copier use policy
- Compensation, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  Memos from principal and superintendent re compensation for missed prep periods
- CSEA (Box 18, Folder 30)
  Agreement by Rhinecliff district recognizing CSEA as bargaining agent for teaching assistants, with salary schedule and other terms, July 1, 1994 through June 30, 1997
- Dinner Theater, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  Westchester Broadway Theatre Group Contract with Rhinecliff school district, for performance of "Nunsense" on March 19, 1993; flyer; theatre party contract for "Camelot," October 27, 1989; seating plans
- D.C.U.T.C., 1999 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  Constitution of the Dutchess County United Teachers' Council, adopted November 1, 1977, amended through March 18, 1999; meeting minutes, April 29 and September 23, 1999
- RTA Duty Charts (Box 18, Folder 33)
  Rhinecliff Teachers Association organizational charts; grievance status report
- Freedom of Information, 1997-1999 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  Letter from RTA president to Robert Freeman, NYS Department of State Committee on Open Government, requesting copies of "Your Right to Know" and text of the Open Meetings law, for distribution to the Rhinecliff Board of Education, September 22, 1997; multiple Freedom of Information requests from Salvia to the Rhinecliff superintendent; correspondence between Salvia and Brother Robert Fontaine, president of the Rhinecliff Board of Education
- Fults, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  Handwritten cover sheet from RTA president to NYSUT labor relations specialist Wally Fults re copies of Improper Practice charge, grievance, and communications from district officials; thank-you note from Fults
- ITU, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  Draft description of Intensive Treatment Unit and Intensive Learning Program, May 13, 1996; memos to principal expressing concern over teacher assistant staffing in ITU, November 4 and 21, 1996; teacher assistant schedule
- Job Descriptions, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  Job descriptions for Rhinecliff/Holy Cross student assistance counselor, director of student safety, superintendent, assistant principal, business manager, guidance counselor, assistant superintendent, and principal
- Humor (Box 18, Folder 38)
  Commentary on low pay and high stress of teaching jobs ("You Might be in Education if..." and memo re Special High Intensity Training)
- Lesson Plan Books, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  Memos re submission of lesson plan books to school administration
- Medical-125 Flex Plan, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  Correspondence between administration and RTA re implementation of new medical plan at Rhinecliff district
- RTA Minutes, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  Minutes of February 8, 1999, meeting of Rhinecliff Teachers Association, including resolution in support of president Joseph Salvia in disciplinary action by district
- NYSUT File, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  Letter to RTA president informing him of a new NYSUT labor relations specialist, Fred Ott, replacing Wally Fults, June 17, 1998; letter from Salvia to NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Staff Director, objecting to change in labor relations specialist while five disciplinary charges were still pending against Salvia, June 22, 1998; letter from Salvia to NYSUT office of general counsel, objecting to another change in disciplinary hearing date, rescheduled to occur during his vacation, May 18, 1998; related correspondence
- NYSUT, 1996-1999 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  List of Mid-Hudson Regional Office stipends and release time, 1995-96 and 1996- 97; request for NYSUT legal review from RTA president re Rhinecliff public comment policy, October 27, 1997; copies of Freedom of Information requests by Salvia; requests to NYSUT from RTA for reimbursement for arbitration expenses
- Office RTA, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  Correspondence re whether two locks or three were needed on door of RTA office, related access issues, February-March 1997; letter from RTA president to superintendent re missing computer from RTA office, noting confidential arbitration records on hard drive, February 24, 1997
- Personal Property Policy, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Lost/Damaged Property Policy; letter to superintendent from RTA president demanding that teachers be reimbursed for losses of personal property
- Press Material, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  Newspaper clippings; letter from RTA president and local newspaper, offering to answer questions re board meeting agenda or policy restricting public comment; letter from Salvia to superintendent requesting mutual press release re contract settlement
- Retirement, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  Correspondence re election of delegates to New York State Teachers' Retirement System
- Salaries, 1989-1998 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  Salary schedules for Rhinecliff school district
- School Budgets (Box 18, Folder 49)
  Guide to budget codes
- School Security, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  Exchange of correspondence between RTA president and district Superintendent Ronald Rosen re locking of school, after Salvia and another teacher were locked in the building for an hour
- Taconic Insurance Administrators, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  Rhinecliff Union Free School District Flex Spending Account: Summary Plan Description; worksheet for qualifying expenses; claim filing instructions; letters from Peter E. Smith Associates/Taconic Insurance Administrators, to RTA president; Flexible Spending Account Proposal for Rhinecliff Union Free School District, submitted by Peter E. Smith Associates/Taconic Insurance Administrators, June 1998
- Student Evaluations (Box 18, Folder 52)
  Blank forms
- Science Teacher, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  Rhinecliff Board of Education minutes of December 10, 1996; letter from teacher objecting to policy requiring teachers to sign in, September 17, 1996; letter to teaher informing him that his position as science teacher was eliminated, August 21, 1997; letter to teacher offering him position, following resignation of another science teacher; salary and other personnel information re teacher
- Sexual Harassment, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  Statements and other materials related to accusations of sexual harassment; letter from Rhinecliff district re finding that the matter did not warrant further investigation, February 2000
- Student Activities Fund, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  Correspondence re use of Student Activities Fund to pay for repairs to car damaged in car wash; personnel information
- Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  Contentious correspondence re various issues
- Dowling, Mary Ann, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  Memo from new district superintendent Mary Ann Dowling re 21-day notice requirement for cancellation of arbitration
- Compensation, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  Correspondence with principal Leslie Hurd over compensation for correcting one test, and other issues
- Personnel Sheet, 1995-2000 (Box 18, Folder 59)
- Personnel Materials, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 60)
  Personnel materials; memo to principal Hurd re ITU (Intensive Treatment Unit) evaluation coverage
- Teacher Observation, 1997-1999 (Box 18, Folder 61)
  Teacher observation; memos re request for more preparation time for after- school activities; personnel materials
- Request for Accrued Time, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 62)
- Appointment Letter, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 63)
- Behavioral Incident Report, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  Behavioral incident report; memo from assistant principal Mahota to RTA president reprimanding him for frivolous incident report; reply from Salvia
- Resume (Box 18, Folder 65)
- Personnel Sheet, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 66)
  Personnel sheet; memos re payroll
- Personnel Sheet, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  Personnel sheet; letter from principal reprimanding him for unauthorized sessions, watching movies with students; letter from superintendent, refusing request to remove principal's letter from personnel file; response to reprimand for being observed taking an unauthorized break at bagel shop during prep time
- Personnel Sheet, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 68)
  Personnel sheet; teacher observation report; request for accrued time for professional development; memo re theft of money from wallet; memos re missing memo
- Personnel Sheet, 1997-1999 (Box 18, Folder 69)
  Personnel sheet; application for position of director of physical education, December 21, 1999; related correspondence; teacher observation report; memo re change in time for treatment team session
- Request for Accrued Time, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 70)
  Request for accrued time for doctor's appointment
- Personnel Sheet, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  Personnel sheet; teacher observation report; response to observation report
- Personnel Sheet, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 72)
  Personnel sheet; certifications; memo
- Personnel Sheet, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 73)
  Personnel sheet; certifications; memo from principal re insubordination; reply by teacher; reply by principal; reply by Valesey; job description for principal; letter from superintendent, noting that job application for principal was received too late to be considered; letter of resignation, noting job offer at another district
- Accusatory Memos, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 74)